(マダラ)
順番が逆になったが まぁいい。
Though things did
happen out of order.
Oh well.
これが 仙術チャクラか…。
So this is Sage Art Chakra...
なんだ この程度の力か。
簡単に扱えそうだな。
Is that all there is to it?
Seems like this will be
easy to control.
(みんな)うわ～っ！
さぁ 次は お前らをいただくぞ。
I'll be taking you all next...
ちくしょうども。
you filthy beasts.
Ready, set, go, we step over the goal line
isse nou se de fumikomu gourain
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
We look back as we pass the line, and it's already gone
issen koete furikaeruto mou nai
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
Fiercely, fiercely we move on
udatte udatte udatteku
Drenched in glistening sweat
kirameku ase ga koboreru no sa
There probably were a lot of things we didn't remember
oboetenai koto mo takusan atta darou
Everyone was just a silhouette
daremo kare mo shiruetto
Let's become adults,
daiji ni shitai mono motte otona ni naru nda
holding on to things we want to cherish
And let's keep on protecting them at all times
donna toki mo hanasazu ni mamori tsudzukeyou
Then someday...
soshitara itsu no hi ni ka
We'll be able to laugh at it all
nanimo kamo o waraerusa
Like the light and nimble dancing
hirari to hirari to matteru
Of leaves taking flight
konoha ga tonde yuku
The Hidden Heart
ここにいるのは…。
You know, staying here...
ああ まずいな…。
Yeah... isn't wise.
ここから離れろ！
Get away from here!
(我愛羅)守鶴 仕込め！
Shukaku! Get ready!
暴れるぜ！
Let's go wild!
《風遁 砂散弾！》
Wind Style...
Sand Bomb! Salvo!
いい術だ。
Nice jutsu.
だが 決定打に欠けるぞ！
But it lacks in finishing power...
ハッ！
お前の砂を埋め込み
自由を奪う術だったか。
So you implant your sand with
this jutsu to stifle movement...
今だ 守鶴！
Now, Shukaku!
《砂漠層大葬封印！》
Grand Sand Mausoleum Seal!
俺様の砂体と
呪印模様を使った大葬封印だ！
It's a Mausoleum Seal
that uses my sand
and curse mark pattern!
(みんな)おおっ。
封印した！
He sealed him!
やったのか？
Did it work?!
もう二度と空気に
触れることはねえぜ ヒャハハハ！
He'll never take another
breath of fresh air again!
うん？
スサノオか…。
The Susano'o, huh!
すぐに首輪をかけてやる。
１匹も逃がしはせん！
I'll be putting collars
on all of you shortly.
Not one of you will
be able to get away.
(ナルト)させっかよ！
I won't let you!
(九喇嘛)テメエに
尻尾ふるヤツはいねえよ！
No one here's going to wag
his tail for you!
遅くなってすまない！
負傷者を移動していた！
Sorry we're late!
We were moving the injured.
大丈夫 もう負傷者が
出ることもないわ 決着よ！
Don't worry!
There won't be any more wounded.
We're ending this now!
尾を重ねろ！
Stack tails!
(みんな)おお～っ！
– Right!
惜しかったな クソ狸！
You were close,
you damned raccoon!
フン！ 偉そうに
命令しやがって バカ狐が！
Quit ordering us around,
you dumb fox!
これで…。
But this should...
しつけぇヤツだ！
Persistent bastard!
でも もうボロボロよ。
But he's already taken a beating.
よっしゃ もうひと息！
All right! One more blast!
ああ 行くぞ ナルト！
Yeah, let's go, Naruto!
(ゼツ)遅くなりました マダラ様。
Sorry I'm late, Lord Madara.
やっと来たか。
You're finally here.
あれは ゼツとかいう…。
Hey, that's Zetsu or
whatever he's called.
援軍か １人で？
Reinforcements? Just one?
♪♪(キラービー)「何しに今頃
遅いぜ 今さら」
What's he doin' here now ♪
Isn't it kinda late? ♪
持っているな？
Do you have it?
もちろんですよ。
Of course.
これで少しは楽しくなるか。
This should make things
a little more fun...
うっ…。
《この血の味 この痛み…》
This taste of blood... this pain!
俺の体だ。
This is my body!
《やっと 戦いを実感できるぞ！》
Finally... I can fully
savor battle again!
アハハハッ！
どうした？ 九喇嘛。
What's wrong, Kurama?
アイツの血…
イヤな感覚を思い出しちまった。
His blood...
It's bringing back some
really bad memories.
血？
Blood?
かつて わしを口寄せした
おぞましい血だ。
That repulsive blood that
summoned me long ago.
ビビッて尾を丸めてんなよ バカ狐。
Hey, you dumb fox! Don't get scared
and stick your tail between your legs!
(九喇嘛)あれをただの
人間だと思って→
I wouldn't underestimate him
if I were you...
甘く見ないほうがいいぜ。
フンッ お前らしくもねえな。
This isn't like you!
気に食わねえ。
It's rubbing me the wrong way!
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
(カカシ)オビト！
Obito!
(ミナト)これで戦おうというのか？
He's gonna fight us using that?
カカシ いけるかい？
Kakashi, can you manage?
えぇ なんとか。
Yes, in one way or another...
神威！
Kamui!
やったかい？
Did it work?
どうやら…。
I think...
失敗したようです。
it failed...
また あれか？
Not that thing again!
右腕をもがれたか。
Seems the right arm's been wrenched off.
向こうにも まだ
いい眼を持ったヤツが→
Seems there's someone left with
good eyes on the other side.
いるようだな。
まぁ 特に支障はない。
Well, it's not much of an impediment.
これで アイツらの小屋はできた。
And now, I've got a pen for them.
あとは ぶち込んでいくだけだ。
All I need to do is
shove them in there.
穢土転生の偽物輪廻眼でも→
A fake Rinnegan from a reanimation
can summon that thing?
あれを口寄せできんのかよ!?
ヤツは血を流し 傷を負ってるわ。
He's bleeding and wounded.
つまり もう穢土転生ではない。
In other words, he's not
a reanimation anymore.
本物の輪廻眼を
持っているのでしょう。
He possesses a real Rinnegan.
どうやって生き返った？
How did he come back to life?!
ナルト お前には感謝している。
Naruto, I'm grateful to you.
オビトから尾獣どもまで
抜いてくれた。
You even extracted
the Tailed Beasts from Obito,
ヤツを弱らせる手間が省けた。
saving me the trouble
of weakening him.
まさか オビトで輪廻天生を…。
Don't tell me with
Obito's Rinne Rebirth...
((いいから来い この野郎！
Now just come over, you bastard!
みんなの力を→
Everyone's power...
(なめんなってばよ！))
Don't you dare underestimate it!
なら オビトは…。
Then Obito's...!
(オビト)ハァッ ハァッ ハァッ…。
オビト…。
Obito...
輪廻眼をマダラの手に渡すまいと
抵抗しているんだ。
He's fighting to prevent
his Rinnegan
from falling into
Madara's hands.
(ゼツ)しつこいな
死にかけのくせに。
You're stubborn,
for someone near death.
この左眼は長門に渡り
お前に行き着いたが→
This left eye came to you
through Nagato,
あるべき本来の場所へ
戻るときなのだ。
but it's time for it to return it
to its rightful owner.
この世に 輪廻眼を開眼した者は→
The only ones who have awakened
the Rinnegan in this world
六道仙人と うちはマダラだけだ。
are the Sage of Six Paths
and Madara Uchiha.
お前のような者が
持っていていい代物ではない！
It's not a mere thing to
be hoarded by the likes of you.
(オビト)右眼は隠した…
左眼は 今 ここでカカシに潰させる。
I've hidden the right eye...
And I'm going to have Kakashi
destroy the left eye right now.
(ゼツ)クックック…。
右眼は 白ゼツが
とっくにみつけていた。
White Zetsu found
the right eye a while ago
すでに マダラ様に渡った。
and turned it over to Lord Madara.
クッ…。
(ゼツ)死にぞこないの用済みが
いちいち抵抗するなよ。
You're a useless fool
who refuses to die...
So stop resisting.
俺がついていなければ
お前は もう死んでいるんだぞ。
You'd be dead already
if I wasn't sticking to you.
ハァ ハァ…
だったら 俺から離れろ。
Then detach from me and
take the Rinnegan after I die.
俺が死んでから
輪廻眼を取ればいいだろう。
(ゼツ)離れたとたん 俺は
コイツら２人に命をとられる。
The instant I detach from you,
these two will kill me.
輪廻眼を取る前にな。
Before I can take the Rinnegan.
俺は 暁の情報収集屋だったのを
忘れたか？
Have you forgotten that
I was the one
who gathered intel for Akatsuki?
コイツら ２人の力も分析済みだ。
I've already analyzed these two
and their strength.
(マダラ)左眼は
もう少しかかりそうだな。
It's going to take a bit longer
for the left eye.
(ゼツ)みたいですね。 こっちも少し
時間がかかりそうだけど…。
Seems like it.
This also looks like it's going
to take a bit longer too.
ペットを連れ戻すのに何年もかかった
ガキと一緒にするな。
Don't compare me to that brat
who took years to get back
those pets.
(ゼツ)血だらけですけど。
You're covered in blood.
(マダラ)柱間の治癒の力が
あるとわかっているぶん→
Knowing that I possess
Hashirama's healing powers
戦い方に優雅さが欠けてしまう。
might cause me to fight crudely.
こっちから行くってばよ！
Let's go!
待て！ ヤツの出方がわからん。
Wait. We don't know how
he's planning to attack.
外道魔像か…。
The Gedo Statue, huh...
もう少し丁寧にいく。
I'll proceed more carefully.
輪廻眼本来の力を使えば→
If I use the Rinnegan's true powers,
高尚な戦いに見えよう。
we should see
a more sophisticated battle.
数秒だ よく見ておけ。
It will only be a few seconds.
So watch closely!
《輪墓 辺獄！》
Limbo...
Hengoku!
何かしてくるかも。
He might try something...
注意を！
So be careful...
うわっ！
ぐあっ！
おっ！
がっ！
うっ!!
ぐっ！
げっ！
がはっ！
ぬあ！
くっ！
《なんだ？ 何が起きた？》
What is this?
What just happened?!
なろっ！
Damn you...
急に 尾獣たちが吹っ飛んだぞ！
The Tailed Beasts got knocked down!
マダラの術なのか？
Was it Madara's jutsu?!
少しは おとなしくなったな。
That ought to have tamed you a bit.
これで やっと首輪をかけられる。
Now I can put on your collars!
何か来るぞ！
Something's coming!
(キラービー)はっつあん！
Eight-o!
九喇嘛！
Kurama!
まずは八尾と九尾を
人柱力から引き剥がす。
First, I'll rip the Eight and
Nine Tails from their Jinchuriki!
はっつあん！
Eight-o!
クソッ！
Damn it!
《そうだ
この九喇嘛モードを解けば…》
That's right...
If I just undo
this Kurama Mode...!
ムダだ 一度捕らえたら離しはせん。
It's useless.
Once I catch them,
I won't let them go.
ダメだ…。
It's not working!
《九喇嘛が俺の中へ戻んねえ》
Kurama's not going
back inside me...!
チクショウ 後ろへ…。
Damn it, I'm being pulled backwards!
マダラ様 一尾から
順に入れるんですよ。
Lord Madara, you must take them
in order starting with the One Tail.
わかっている。
I know that.
(ゼツ)人柱力から
引き剥がす尾獣が→
Since you need to rip out
the last two Tailed Beasts,
ちょうど後半の八尾と九尾なら
その間 一尾から七尾までは→
Eight and Nine Tails,
from the Jinchuriki,
why not pull in the others,
the one tail through seven
in the time being?
ぶち込んじゃったらどうですか？
なろ… 九喇嘛を
取られてたまるか！
You bastard! I'm not letting you
take Kurama!
そうだな 思ったより粘りそうだ。
You're right, it looks like this will
take longer than I expected.
まずは… コイツからだ！
So let's start... with this one!
《砂漠 叛奴！》
Desert Hands!
守鶴は渡さん！
You can't have Shukaku!
((お前が眠りに入ったら
俺様がお前の心と体を乗っ取り→
When you fall asleep,
I'll take over your body and soul...
お前ら人間どもを
皆殺しにしてやる！
And slaughter all you humans!
うかつに熟睡しないことだ。
Better not doze off.
お前は 人間が嫌いなの？
You hate humans?
ああ 大嫌いだ!!
Yeah! I despise them!
でも お前は僕の里を
守るためにいるんでしょ？
But... You're here to protect
my village, aren't you?
誰がすき好んで
お前らなんかを守るか！
I've never protected you all
because I wanted to.
お前ら人間は 俺たち獣以下だ！
You humans are less than us beasts!
ほら 飯だ守鶴。
Here's your meal, Shukaku!
なんで上役になってまで→
Why do we have to stand guard
over a creepy, weird monk
こんな薄気味悪い坊主の
見張りをしなきゃならんのだ。
even though we're senior shinobi?
まったくだが
人柱力の見張りを任されるのは→
I know what you mean.
But guarding the Jinchuriki means
they recognize your skills.
力を認められている証拠。
今は我慢しろ。
Just stop whining and deal with it.
クソ坊主 お前はもう→
Poor damned monk.
They don't even call you by
your real name anymore.
自分の名前ですら
呼んでもらえなくなったな。
それは別によいのです。
I don't really mind.
あなたが私の本当の名を
知ってくれていますから。
Since you know my real name.
いくら坊主でも お前を嫌う
人間どもに手を合わせ→
You may be a monk,
but don't you ever get lonely...
putting up with humans
who hate you, and a beast like me?
獣の俺様なんかを相手に
いい加減 寂しくねえのかよ!?
生まれてこのかた→
Caged together with
a man-hating beast
ずっと人間嫌いの獣と一緒に
檻の中でよ。
that's been with you ever
since you were born?
どのみち 私はあなたと
離れたとたんに死んでしまいます。
Well, I'd die the moment
I'm separated from you...
人柱力ですから。
Since I'm a Jinchuriki.
そもそも 人と獣
それらを分ける必要はないのです。
There's no need to distinguish
between human and beast.
なんであれ 心の友がいれば
心の平和が満たされるのです。
That's because a friend of
the heart provides peace of mind,
no matter the species.
まったく 変わったクソじじいだぜ。
You are one strange bastard.
お前みたいな人間は
これからも いやしねえだろうよ。
There isn't ever going to be
another human like you again.
いや そんなことはありませんよ。
No...
I think you're wrong.
人の心とは水鏡。
Human souls are like reflecting water.
本心とは裏腹に口を開き
揺れ動くものです。
People often speak or act opposite
of their true feelings.
ですが 元来 人間の持つ
裏の心は→
But essentially,
the human heart wishes
受け入れ合うことを
望んでいるのです。
to connect with and
accept each other.
獣ともです。
Even with beasts.
お前 やっぱ
六道仙人のじじいに似てるな。
You know...
you really do remind me of
the old man, Sage of Six Paths.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
今まで あなたからいただいた
言葉の中で→
Those are the most heartwarming words
I've ever received from you.
ひと際 嬉しい言葉です。
さっさと食えよ じじい！
片づかねえだろ。
Hurry up and eat, old man!
We've got things to do here!
ケッ！ 本当にお前みたいなヤツが
他にいるとは思えねえがな。
I really can't see there being
others like you out there.
きっといます。
I'm sure there are.
そして あなたには→
And I know one day,
あなたを守り 導く者が
必ずや現れるでしょう。
there will be someone who will protect,
redeem, and shepherd you.
そして その者の裏の心を
受け入れたとき→
And the moment you come
to accept his true heart,
あなたも悟るでしょう。
you too will likely comprehend...
(私の師が 私の手に刻んでくれた
言葉の意味を))
The meaning of these words
my mentor etched onto my palms...
ACCEPTANCE HEART
LOVE
我愛羅 負けんなよ！
Gaara, don't lose!
((お前のことは
今まで疎ましく思ってきた。
Until now, I've always
considered you unpleasant.
だが 人柱力であったからこそ
ナルトに会うことができた。
But it was because
I was a Jinchuriki,
that I was able to meet Naruto...
(お前に感謝することが
一つだけできた))
So there's one thing
I'm grateful to you for now.
砂のガキめ そんなに かつてのペットが
帰ってきて嬉しいか。
You Sand brat!
Are you really that happy
to have your old pet back?
人柱力で死ぬわけでもないのに
邪魔しやがって。
How dare you interfere,
even when you're not going
to die as a Jinchuriki!
俺様のモットーは 絶対防御だ！
My motto is absolute defense!
守鶴としてのプライドもあるんでな。
I've still got my pride as Shukaku!
わかっている。
I know...
いや 何もわかっちゃいないな。
No... you know nothing at all.
ぐおぉ！
kimi ni makechai sou na kurai
Almost to the point of losing to you
kimi ni nayamasare sou da
Feeling like you might torment me
kimi ni kikoecha dame dame dame da
Not wanting you to hear me no, no, no
kimi ni nagasare sou na kurai
Swept away by you
kimi ni shiteyarare sou da
Taken in by you
kimi o omoccha dame dame dame da
I shouldn't love you no, no, no
sugu wasurechatte dame da
It's not good that I'm so forgetful
uzukumattecha dame da
It's not good that I'm cowering
kizutsuitatte ana aitatte
Even if I'm wounded and pierced
massugu tatteirareruyou ni naritai
I want to be able to stand up straight
kimi ni makechai sou na kurai
Almost to the point of losing to you
kimi ni nayamasare sou da
Feeling like you might torment me
kimi ni kikoecha dame dame dame da
Not wanting you to hear me no, no, no
kimi ni nagasare sou na kurai
Swept away by you
kimi ni shiteyarare sou da
Taken in by you
kimi o omoccha dame dame dame da
I shouldn't love you no, no, no
People desire peace.
<旬の小鉢が大好きな豆助>
And yet on the other hand,
crave conflict as well.
♪～
That's right, Hashirama's nation-building
bore a paradox.
People will sacrifice something in order
to protect something else.
≫豆助
きょうは今が旬の
アレを使った小鉢よ？
Stop Madara! Don't you—!
< その小鉢とは？>
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"A True Ending"
I gave you plenty enough time
How unfortunate.
< それは収穫したのち…>